ICI Lombard has introduced a very
Innovative integrated media initiative
called Game of Life this pioneering
Concept in the insurance domain combines
the excitement of gaming with the
practicality of insurance this campaign
leverages the captivating Allure of
virtual games to connect with the
digital native generation while while
speaking about the uncertainties and ups
and downs of our everyday life while
urging the viewers to stay protected to
tell us more we are joined in by Sheena
Kapoor head marketing corporate
Communications and CSR ICICI Lombard
Shea welcome to CNBC TV8 thank you so
much and it's pleasure to be here China
first of all game of life I saw the
campaign such an interesting concept
tell us more about it how it was
conceptualized what were some of the
discussions that you had with your
agency oal V I believe um and what was
the kind of brief that you gave to them
for us game of life has been a very uh
disruptive campaign and uh as always you
know with any bfsi sector Q4 happens to
be like the most active uh season and uh
we started actually thinking and
ideating about scripts uh way back in uh
Q3 about October November so that we're
you know well in time ready uh with the
plan and uh we actually went through
some six to seven very interesting
scripts um and we looked at different
kind of narratives uh we were sure that
we wanted to talk about something which
was at a brand level which was at an
corporate level uh a campaign that spoke
about icsl Lombard but spoke about a
different tonality and spoke about the
category uh we wanted to have something
which was a culmination of uh technology
um ideation uh creativity uh Innovation
and uh is yet very engaging um you know
for the viewers especially something
that engages and appeals to the younger
audience the Millennials and the Gen Z
and gamification so how did you arrive
upon gamifying uh you know to
communicate the objective of buying an
insurance Life's a game you really don't
know what will happen next it's so
uncertain you can't really predict
because it is unpredictable um and
insurance therefore you know as a
category we're there uh to be um you
know providing that shield and that
protection uh cover for the consumers
across whether it's you know health
insurance or whether it's motor
insurance uh to safeguard the consumers
um you know against these kind of
uncertainties as well as protecting the
assets um and so we asked ourselves okay
here is this gamification route can
weing bring alive the entire concept and
bring it in the environment of a gaming
so that we make it even more cooler and
we make it more engaging and uh you know
and I think it's resonated uh very well
of course with the younger audience but
I'm happy to say that that even uh with
the older demographics it has resonated
really well so having said that I'm
tempted to ask what has it done for ICI
Lombard uh or what can it potentially do
for the brand as compared to what you
know the traditional uh campaign would
have done so you know um again this is
far removed from anywhere close to what
traditional uh has done so far and in
fact arguably uh not just within the
insurance not even within the bfsi I'm
saying across categories um and i' I'd
go bold enough to say within India and
arguably even across the world this is
the first time any brand has attempted a
narrative which is using a gaming
environment and uh the production house
the creative agencies the director has
pulled this off so fabulously that it
actually looks like robotic characters
when they're actually humans who are uh
portraying the entire film narrative um
and through the film like I said you
know we have spoken about um you know
the different aspects of life and we've
brought up the analogy with health bar
or the power bar like you have in a game
so anything that you do which is um you
know um which could leave you wable uh
to any kind of mishap or is actually you
know taking away from your well-being
actually depletes your energy so you
reaching out for junk food even though
you know that a healthier choice exists
uh is actually not doing too you know
too great for you in the health terms in
the longer run right um and that's what
we're trying to also advocate to the
audience saying preventive uh healthare
and the overall well-being and the
Continuum of Care that we want to
propose um and as against any kind of
traditional adwar you would have
possibly taken a product you know
exemplified the features or um you know
the Contours of the product or you know
as as a lot of brands do you know engage
with even ROP in some celebrities you
know to uh pull off the narrative this
is you know extremely differentiated uh
disruptive original and very very
refreshing in fact I have been I think
the best form of uh you know uh you know
compliment that one can receive is from
the competition itself you know and from
the a lot of the marketeers you know
from within the insurance and bfsi
category uh they've come forward to you
know congratulate uh us on the campaign
and have been saying that you know this
has really raised the bar uh from an
otherwise a very boring category which
is uh uh which is kind of you know used
to doing some boring work and not like
very disruptive work thank you so much
thanks for joining us today and thanks
for sharing these insights with us she
thank you thank you so
much